日常工作
翻译：桃了  压制：感康小快客
校对 & 后期：@Phuckq
日记
【三次元成瘾者康复中心】倾情奉献
更多动画 新浪@Kresent
本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
我们晚点再去啦
Dude, let's water them later.
不  我们现在就去帮玛格丽特浇花
No! We're watering Margaret's plants now!
- 你对她还真是言听计从  - 我才没有咧
- You're so whipped. - No, I'm not.
才怪  你简直成了她的奴隶...
Yeah right! You're whipped with a capital...
帮我浇花就是了
Just help me water the plants!
这公寓真棒
This place is awesome!
噢  烤架
Aw, yeah! Grill!
等我们正式交往以后  我一定请你过来吃汉堡
After we start dating, I'll totally invite you over for burgers.
随便你  我们能不能快点搞定收工走人
Whatever! Can we just get this over with so we can leave?
别这么扫兴嘛
Chill, dude!
我真不敢相信  玛格丽特周末不在家时
I can't believe Margaret asked us to water her plants
会委托我们来照顾她的盆栽
while she's gone for the weekend.
我想这意味着一定程度的信任
I think this really shows a level of trust.
你想太多了
I think you're reading too much into it.
她只是叫你帮她浇花
All she did was ask you to water her plants.
是是是  反正我可没看见谁找你帮他们浇花
Yeah, well, I don't see anyone asking you to water their plants.
老天  她的盆栽还真多
Man, she's got a lot of plants!
真不敢相信  你竟然告诉她你会给所有花浇水
I can't believe you told her you'd water all these.
有你这么笨的吗
What a chump.
那是因为玛格丽特是我的朋友
It's because Margaret's my friend.
对  一个捞不着好处的朋友
Yeah, your friend without benefits.
嘿  别再胡说八道了  快帮我找水壶吧
Hey, shut up and help me find the watering can.
卧室门锁住了
Agh, the bedroom door's locked!
水壶不可能在她卧室里  离那远点
It wouldn't be in her bedroom! Stay out of there!
摩迪凯 我和他没什么啦
Oh, Mordecai, he's alright.
我们又没有约会什么的
It's not like we're dating or anything.
我只是叫他偶尔过来帮我浇个花
I just let him come over and water my plants sometimes.
嘿  把那个放回去
Hey, put that back!
不 我就想在浇花的时候戴着这帽子
No. I wanna wear it while I water the plants.
放回去啦
Put it back!
求我啊
Make me.
放手啦  我要戴着它浇花
Get off of me! I wanna wear it while I water the plants!
瞧你做的好事
Dude, what did you do?!
什么叫我做的好事  明明是你推我的
What do you mean, what did I do?! You pushed me!
你把它弄坏了
Dude, you broke it!
得了吧  书又摔不烂
Yeah right, you can't break books!
就算真的摔坏了
And besides, even if it did break,
把它放回原位  不说出去就好了
just put it back and don't say anything!
你真的把它弄坏了
Dude, you totally broke it!
瞧  这东西上面有锁
Look, this thing has a lock on it.
什么  什么样的书上面会有锁?
What? What kind of book has a lock on it?
我不知道
I don't know.
这本日记属于
玛格丽特
糟了
Oh no.
- 咋了  - 这是玛格丽特的日记
- What? - This is Margaret's diary!
她肯定会以为我偷看了她的日记
Dude, she's gonna think I was reading her diary!
这下糟了
This is bad.
有什么大不了的
Dude, what's the big deal?
不就是本烂日记嘛
It's just some lame old diary!
我的意思是  这年头还谁还需要保守秘密
I mean, why do people even need to keep secrets?
我就没有秘密
I don't have any secrets.
你有什么秘密吗 反正我是没有
Do you have any secrets? I know I sure don't.
我才不管
I don't care!
要是她回来以后发现这东西坏了
If she comes home and finds this thing broken,
肯定会以为我偷看了
she's gonna think I read it!
我们得在她回来之前修好它
We have to fix it before she gets back.
拜托  拜托
Come on, come on.
你能不能冷静点  没胶水那东西能黏得牢吗
Will you chill out? It's not gonna stick without glue.
看样子瑞格比又要施以援手了
Agh, looks like Rigby has to bail you out again.
这个好  "超级胶水"
Aw yeah, "Supe the Glup."
- 滴一滴就好哦  - 我知道
- Dude, just a drop. - I know.
- 只要一滴  - 我知道啦
- Just a drop! - I know!
我说了"只要一滴"
Dude, I said "Just a drop!"
都是你害得我紧张兮兮的
You were making me nervous!
给我看看胶水的说明
Aw man! Let me see that glue.
好  好  好
Ok, ok, ok.
上面说我们可以用加热的方法去除胶水
It says here we can remove the glue with heat.
交给我吧
Let me handle it.
等等
Wait.
我们不能再把东西丢进微波炉了
We're not putting anthing in the microwave.
- 起作用了  - 没错
- Dude, it's working. - Yeah, it is.
让我来  让我来
I got it. I got it.
那不是...
Dude, that's not--!
你觉得她还会发现吗?
You think she'll notice?
你能修好它吗
Can you fix it?
这是啥
What is this?
玛格丽特的日记
It's Margaret's diary.
为啥它看起来不像
Why does it look like that?
说来话长
It's a long story.
抱歉  这东西用普通方法可修不好
Sorry, this can't be fixed without traditional methods.
那你能用不普通的方法修吗
Well do you have any un-traditional ones?
当然可以  有个方法
Of course. There is one way,
我可以用魔法鹅毛笔复制一本全新的日记
I could transfer to a new diary using a magic quil pen.
太感谢你了  跳跳
Thank you, Skips.
要完成这个仪式
In order for this to work,
我们就必须回到这本日记被弄坏的地点
we have to be in the same place where the diary was broken.
玛格丽特家
Margaret's house.
但在这之前我必须警告你们
But first I want you both to know is that
日记是严肃神圣的  因为日记里保守着秘密
diaries are a serious business, cause they can contain secrets.
而秘密则需不计代价的守护
And secrets must be protected at all cost.
- 好的跳跳  我们懂了  - 真的吗?
- Yeah Skips we know. - Do you?
听着  为了尊重和保守玛格丽特的秘密
Look, out of respect for Margaret's secrets,
我愿意帮你们
I'm gonna help you guys.
但是  你们必须严肃对待此事  并完全找我说的做
But, you have to take it seriously and do exacty as I say.
好的跳跳  我们保证做到
Yeah, Skips, we promise.
是的  我们保证做到
Yeah, we promise.
你们最好是说到做到
Well you better,
秘密的力量可不容小觑
because secrets are a force to be reckoned with.
不是吧 这看起来可完全不像玛格丽特的日记
Ah, what?! That doesn't look anything like Margaret's diary.
一旦书写仪式完成
As in written content,
这两本日记的外观和内容将会一模一样
so too in physical appearance, will the books become identical.
好了  牵起手来
Alright, guys, join hands.
我才不要牵手
I'm not gonna hold hands!
来吧  照他说的做  他正在帮我们解决问题
C'mon, dude, just do it, he's tryin' to help us out.
好啦
Fine.
好  是时候开始了
Okay, it's time to begin.
从现在起  不管你们听到什么
Now, no matter what ya hear,
都不能偷看魔法鹅毛笔抄写玛格丽特的秘密
you musn't look at Margaret's thoughts as the quill transfers the secrets.
现在我们必须闭上眼睛
Now we must all close our eyes.
瑞格比  闭上你的眼睛
Rigby, close your eyes.
好好好  我闭上就是
Fine, I'm closin' em.
仪式开始
Begin.
它们在说什么
What're they saying?
闭着眼睛  不要理会那些声音
Just keep your eyes closed and ignore them.
这仪式要花多久时间
HOW MUCH LONGER IS THIS GONNA TAKE?!
不确定  闭着眼睛就是了
It should be any minute, just keep your eyes closed!
酷
Cool.
仪式并未完成
The transfer is incomplete.
大家都是闭着眼睛的吗
Did everyone keep their eyes shut?
我一直闭着
I kept mine shut!
怎么
What?!
好啦
Alright, fine!
我可能偷看了那么一下下  可能
There's a chance I might've maybe probably looked. Maybe.
瑞格比
RIGBY!
你知道你做了什么吗
Do you have any idea what you've done?!
什么声音
What is that?
从外头传来的
It's coming from outside.
玛格丽特
Margaret?!
那不是玛格丽特  当瑞格比偷看时...
That's not Margaret. When Rigby looked--
我说了可能  可能
I SAID MAYBE LOOKED, MAYBE!
他释放出了玛格丽特秘密的守护者
He released the Guardian of Margaret's Secrets.
她会因为我们偷看了秘密而毁灭我们
She will destroy us for looking at her secrets.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?!
只有一个挽救的方法
There's only one way to stop this.
我们每个人吐露一个自己的秘密
Each of us must reveal a secret of our own,
不然她就会灭了我们
or she'll destroy us.
好吧  我先来
Alright. I'll go first.
我一直以跳代走的原因
The reason I always skip is,
是为了我这辈子  心里唯一思念过的女人
in all my life, my heart yearned for only one woman.
我们在一起时总是蹦蹦跳跳的
And we used to skip together all the time.
直到有天我失去了她
On the day I lost her,
我发誓余生的每一天都要蹦蹦跳跳的
I vowed to skip every day for the rest of my life,
这样我才不会忘记我们在一起时的美好时光
so that I'd never forget the time we spent together.
起..起作用了  现在快说出你们的秘密
I-IT'S WORKIN'! NOW TELL YOUR SECRETS!
好吧...
Okay...
有时我们要清理排水沟时
sometimes when we're supposed to be cleaning out gutters,
我们其实是去喝咖啡了
we go to get coffee instead!
对  对  这个不错
Yeah, yeah, good one!
而且其中有很多次  我甚至都没点咖啡
And a lot of times, I don't even get coffee!
我只是不喜欢清理排水沟
I just don't feel like cleaning out the gutters!
不行  必须是有意义的秘密
No, it has to be something meaningful!
要有多大意义才行啊
HOW MEANINGFUL DOES IT HAVE TO BE?!
如果你们不告诉她一个真正的秘密  我们就死定了
IF YOU DON'T TELL A REAL SECRET, WE'RE ALL GONNA DIE!
好了好了  我来
ALL RIGHT, I'LL DO IT!
我喜欢跟着唱一些超烂的口水歌
I LIKE TO SING ALONG TO REALLY BAD POP MUSIC!
我吃过从垃圾桶里翻出来的甜甜圈
I ATE A DOUGHNUT OUTTA THE TRASH!
我喜欢不穿内裤
I LIKE GOING COMMANDO!
经常不穿
A LOT!
我其实觉得从垃圾桶里翻出来的甜甜圈更好吃
I ACUALLY LIKE THE TASTE OF DOUGHNUTS BETTER WHEN THEY'RE FROM THE TRASH!
瑞格比  还记得我们预订了床垫
RIGBY! REMEMBER WHEN WE ORDERED BEDS FOR OUR ROOM
但你的那块却一直没送来吗  其实我撒了谎
AND YOUR'S NEVER SHOWED UP?! I LIED!
我把两块床垫叠在一起了 我一直枕着它们
I STACKED THEM UP AND I'VE BEEN SLEEPING ON THEM THE WHOLE TIME!
我很抱歉  因为那实在是太舒服了
I'M SORRY, DUDE, IT'S JUST TOO COMFORTABLE!
你是说真的
Are you serious?
瑞格比  继续说
RIGBY! SAY SOMETHING!
我小时候偷了邻居的自行车  还把它扔在了屋顶上
WHEN I WAS LITTLE, I STOLE MY NEIGHBOR'S BIKE AND THREW IT ON THE ROOF!
必须要更有意义的秘密
IT HAS TO BE SOMETHING DEEP!
有时我会藏起帕布的鞋子
SOMETIMES I HIDE POPS' SHOES
因为我觉得他找鞋的样子很搞笑
CAUSE I THINK IT'S FUNNY WHEN HE'S LOOKING FOR THEM!
我是个讨厌的家伙
I'M A HORRIBLE PERSON!
我讨厌洗澡  讨厌猫咪
I HATE TAKING SHOWERS AND I HATE KITTENS!
我其实没参加过足球队
I LIED ABOUT BEING ON THE FOOTBALL TEAM!
我觉得艾琳不戴眼镜的时候很迷人
I THINK EILEEN IS HOT WITHOUT HER GLASSES ON!
让我们完成仪式
Let's finish this!
看起来和玛格丽特那本一模一样
It looks exactly like Margaret's!
跳跳  我们该怎么报答你
Skips, how can we repay you?
还记得我说为什么我要以跳代走吗
You remember that stuff I said about why I skip?
- 记得啊  - 不  当你们没听过
- Yeah. - No, ya don't.
我知道你睡了我的床垫
I knew it was my matress.
艾琳  是吧
So, Eileen, huh?
闭嘴
STOP TALKING!
真不敢相信  我们修复了日记
I can't believe we got the diary back together.
是啊  累惨了
Yeah, what a pain.
我再也不要帮玛格丽特浇花了
I never wanna water Margaret's plants ever again.
等等  我们到底帮她浇了花没
Wait, did we actually ever water her plants?
她来了
Here she comes!
嘿  玛格丽特  旅行顺利吗
Oh, hey Margaret! How was your trip?
还不错  但我也只能忍受我爸妈这么久了
It was nice, but i can only take my parents for so long, you know?
快跟我说说  父母都很可怕
Tell me about it, 'rents are the worst.
你不用担心你的盆栽
Well, you don't have to worry about your plants,
而且你公寓的屋顶也还在  还有...
or if the roof is still on your apartment, or whatever.
我的意思就是一切都好
Because it's fine is what I meant.
你们没去帮我浇花吧
You guys didn't go and water them, did you?
去了呀  怎么
Yeah, why?
我忘记其实我已经拜托过艾琳了
I forgot that I already asked Eileen to do it.
真的吗
Really?
是的  她整个周末都待在卧室里呢
Yeah, she had the spare bedroom all weekend.
很抱歉给你们添了这么多麻烦
Sorry you guys went through all that trouble.
没见着她  我想是正好错过了
I guess we just missed each other,
所以别放在心上
So don't worry about it.
对 没关系的
Yeah, it's cool.
两位  这是你们点的咖啡
Hey, guys, here's your coffee.